<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Application Development for the Google Cloud Platform on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/</link><description>Recent content in Application Development for the Google Cloud Platform on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our ways of working</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="our-ways-of-working">Our ways of working&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In small, cross-functional teams, we have been building successful software products for digital business models iteratively and data-driven for over 26 years. Each Team includes a Team Lead, who is a software engineer themself and writes code every day. Team Leads are also usually trained as Product Owners and are appreciated as contacts for the Product Owner on the client side. A Site Reliability Engineer works with each team to automate all development and operational processes and establishes effective monitoring. Each team is completed by experienced UI/UX Designers, an Engineering Director for major technological decisions and a Commercial Lead who also keeps an eye on the team’s KPIs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Application development from start to end</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="application-development-from-start-to-end">Application development from start to end&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>To understand the client’s requirements and goals and align our ways of working, we set up a series of workshops with our new clients covering:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>- Different business cases&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>- Looking at complete customer user journeys&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>- Demonstrating possible solutions&lt;/strong>&lt;br>
&lt;strong>- Setting up initial prioritized and estimated backlogs based on MoSCoW method&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Our self built tool Revolution enables the teams to work autonomously and create reproducible results. In Revolution, an engineering team creates structured backlogs and prioritizes on an epic and story level. Those backlogs help the engineering teams to plan their project roadmaps more carefully.&lt;br>
Every team has a long-term view of each project and plans based on daily real-time data. Revolution also provides KPIs in real-time about the reliability and progress of a team.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Our public customer success stories</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="our-public-customer-success-stories">Our public customer success stories&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Using the Google Cloud Platform, we successfully migrated many of our clients to the cloud. With two of them we have published success stories to which you can find more information below. Many more are to come.&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="flex flex-wrap my-12">
 




&lt;article class="md:w-1/3 lg:w-2/5">
 &lt;div class="mb-12 md:mr-8 md:mb-8 lg:mr-16 lg:mb-16 bg-pale-purple">
 &lt;img src="https://freiheit.com//img/things-weve-built/hyper-scalable-e-commerce-system.png.webp" class="w-full" alt="Hyper-Scalable E-Commerce System"/>
 &lt;div class="p-5">
 &lt;h5 class="mt-0 text-body-xl">Hyper-Scalable E-Commerce System&lt;/h5>
 &lt;div class="text-body-lg font-light">
 We helped the coffee house and seasonal retailer Tchibo to revolutionize its multinational e-commerce website. Going from on-premises to &lt;a class="font-serif no-underline hover:text-red" href="https://cloud.google.com/customers/tchibo" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Cloud Platform&amp;nbsp;→&lt;/a> relieved the company’s IT-professionals and made it possible to break down the system’s monolithic core into microservices. Our engineers integrated dozens of interfaces to legacy-backend systems with zero downtime of the shop, minimizing impact on customer service and business transactions.
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/article>







&lt;article class="md:w-2/3 lg:w-3/5">
 &lt;div class="mb-12 md:mr-8 md:mb-8 lg:mr-16 lg:mb-16 bg-red">
 &lt;img src="https://freiheit.com//img/things-weve-built/global-b2b-retail-platform_2.jpg.webp" class="w-full" alt="Global B2B Retail Platform"/>
 &lt;div class="p-5">
 &lt;h5 class="mt-0 text-body-xl">Global B2B Retail Platform&lt;/h5>
 &lt;div class="text-body-lg font-light">
 For the food giant METRO we have built a large-scale e-commerce platform and rolled it out to 20+ countries. After just under five years, the system now generates over 4 billion euros per year and has become one of the largest &lt;a class="font-serif no-underline hover:text-red" href="https://cloud.google.com/customers/metro" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Cloud&amp;nbsp;→&lt;/a> customers in Europe.
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/article>







&lt;article class="md:w-2/3 lg:w-3/5">
 &lt;div class="mb-12 md:mr-8 md:mb-8 lg:mr-16 lg:mb-16 bg-red">
 &lt;img src="https://freiheit.com//img/things-weve-built/DS_PrimeSolutions_2072_1.webp" class="w-full" alt="Connected Cloud Services for Dentsply Sirona"/>
 &lt;div class="p-5">
 &lt;h5 class="mt-0 text-body-xl">Connected Cloud Services for Dentsply Sirona&lt;/h5>
 &lt;div class="text-body-lg font-light">
 With one of the world’s largest manufacturers of professional dental products and technologies, we have built a cloud ecosystem that lets dentists collect and process 3D image data in the cloud right from their scanning device. The service enables real-time cloud collaboration between specialists and ordering 3D printed oral appliances with strict GDPR compliance. This first-of-its-kind solution not only gives our client a competitive advantage, but also streamlines healthcare services for millions of patients around the globe. &lt;a class="font-serif no-underline hover:text-red" href="https://freiheit.com/downloads/Connecting_Dental_Clinics_to_the_Cloud_Dentsply_Sirona.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Read More&amp;nbsp;→&lt;/a>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/article>




&lt;article class="md:w-1/3 lg:w-2/5">
 &lt;div class="mb-12 md:mr-8 md:mb-8 lg:mr-16 lg:mb-16 bg-pale-purple">
 &lt;img src="https://freiheit.com//img//things-weve-built/peek-and-cloppenburg.webp" class="w-full" alt="Peek &amp;amp; Cloppenburg"/>
 &lt;div class="p-5">
 &lt;h5 class="mt-0 text-body-xl">Peek &amp;amp; Cloppenburg&lt;/h5>
 &lt;div class="text-body-lg font-light">
 Partnering with Peek &amp;amp; Cloppenburg, we harnessed &lt;a class="font-serif no-underline hover:text-red" href="https://cloud.google.com/customers/peek-cloppenburg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Google Cloud&amp;nbsp;→&lt;/a> to develop a sophisticated omnichannel platform, seamlessly merging online and in-store experiences. This initiative accelerated revenue through smart recommendations and personalized marketing, freeing resources for value-driven innovation, and pioneering a shift in the retail industry towards a data-driven, customer-centric future.
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
 &lt;/div>
&lt;/article>


&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>