<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Application Development for the Google Cloud Platform on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/</link><description>Recent content in Application Development for the Google Cloud Platform on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Application Development for the Google Cloud Platform</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</guid><description>Our Ways of Working In small, cross-functional teams, we have been building successful software products for digital business models iteratively and data-driven for over 23 years. Each Team includes a Team Lead, who is a software engineer themself and writes code every day. Team Leads are also usually trained as Product Owners and are appreciated as contacts for the Product Owner on the client side. A Site Reliability Engineer works with each team to automate all development and operational processes and establishes effective monitoring.</description></item><item><title>Application Development from Start to End</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</guid><description>Application Development from Start to End To understand the client’s requirements and goals and align our ways of working, we set up a series of workshops with our new clients covering:
- Different business cases
- Looking at complete customer user journeys
- Demonstrating possible solutions
- Setting up initial prioritized and estimated backlogs based on MoSCoW method
Our self built tool Revolution enables the teams to work autonomously and create reproducible results.</description></item><item><title>Our Public Customer Success Stories with Metro and Tchibo</title><link>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</guid><description>Our Public Customer Success Stories with Metro and Tchibo Using the Google Cloud Platform, we successfully migrated many of our clients to the cloud. With two of them we have published success stories to which you can find more information below. Many more are to come.
Hyper-Scalable E-Commerce System We helped the coffee house and seasonal retailer Tchibo to revolutionize its multinational e-commerce website. Going from on-premises to Google Cloud Platform&amp;nbsp;→ relieved the company’s IT-professionals and made it possible to break down the system’s monolithic core into microservices.</description></item></channel></rss>