<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>podcast on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/tags/podcast/</link><description>Recent content in podcast on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/tags/podcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Episode one</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-01/</guid><description>In his early twenties, Greg started as a Stanford Grad at Google, went through the famous APM program and then went on as one of the early engineers at Instagram, He was there when Facebook acquired it. Now he is living in NYC and we will talk about the life of a product manager and software engineer in Silicon Valley.</description></item><item><title>How to make your systems highly available and fast</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/why-agile-is-not-enough/why-agile-is-not-enough-01/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/why-agile-is-not-enough/why-agile-is-not-enough-01/</guid><description>What have we learned in building our own SRE organization over the last five years?
What are the most important first steps when building up a strong SRE organization?
How can you transform your operations staff into a powerful SRE team?</description></item><item><title>Episode two</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-02/</guid><description>From Product Manager at Google to CEO at Lever: Stefan Richter talked with Sarah Nahm. After working as a product manager at Google, she founded Lever, a company that changed recruiting worldwide. Sarah will tell us her story and how the Associate Product Management Program (APM) at Google helped her to become a CEO of her own company.</description></item><item><title>How to build and run an efficient software engineering organization</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/why-agile-is-not-enough/why-agile-is-not-enough-02/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/why-agile-is-not-enough/why-agile-is-not-enough-02/</guid><description>Running a software project is still hard and a lot of companies still struggle to make their teams efficient, productive and successful. As many companies have already noticed, working “agile” is also not the silver bullet.
Stefan Richter, Founder and Head of Engineering of freiheit.com, shares his insights on how to empower teams to manage themselves.</description></item><item><title>Episode three</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-03/</guid><description>How METRO moved into the cloud, created a billion-euro global business platform and reinvented their IT organization.</description></item><item><title>How To Optimize Engineering Productivity</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/why-agile-is-not-enough/why-agile-is-not-enough-03/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/why-agile-is-not-enough/why-agile-is-not-enough-03/</guid><description>Stefan Richter, Founder &amp;amp; Head of Engineering @ freiheit.com, talks about engineering productivity: a data-driven engineering discipline focused on optimizing the engineering process so that organizations can deliver amazing experiences to their users faster.</description></item><item><title>Episode four</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-04/</guid><description>Sven Lipowski and Stefan Richter started METRO’s first digital transformation project in 2015. He shares their insights on how they started METRO’s biggest digitization project together, from the first workshop until making €4 billion turnover per year with a highly scalable microservice platform running in 24 countries.</description></item><item><title>Episode five</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-05/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-05/</guid><description>Frerk Lätari and Stefan Richter share their key challenges and insights on how to do a successful lift &amp;amp; shift into the Google Cloud of one of Germany’s largest e-commerce systems within three months.</description></item><item><title>Episode six</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-06/</guid><description>After studying logistics &amp;amp; e-business in Remagen and playing bass in jazz clubs at night for a living, Sascha became a management consultant after he earned his first product management chops in the telco industry. Then he became a founding member of the product team at MOIA and launched this new kind of mobility service in Hamburg in 2019. He will share a good amount of war stories from this amazing journey.</description></item><item><title>Episode seven</title><link>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-07/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/chronicle/humans-in-tech/humans-in-tech-episode-07/</guid><description>Jackie Bavaro started her career as a PM at Microsoft and Google. At Google, Jackie was part of the famous APM program and worked as a Product Manager for the Google Data APIs and Google Search. In 2011, Jackie joined Asana as the company’s first Product Manager before she later became the Head of Product Management. Jackie is also the co-author of the famous book “Cracking the PM Interview: How to Land a Product Manager Job in Technology”.</description></item></channel></rss>