<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Things we've build on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/</link><description>Recent content in Things we've build on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 15:55:09 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Global B2B Retail Platform</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/global-b2b-retail-platform/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/global-b2b-retail-platform/</guid><description>For the food giant METRO we have built a large-scale e-commerce platform and rolled it out to 20+ countries. After just under five years, the system now generates over 4 billion euros per year and has become one of the largest Google Cloud customers in Europe.</description></item><item><title>Site Reliability Engineering &amp; Infrastructure as Code</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/site-reliability-engineering-infrastructure-as-code/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/site-reliability-engineering-infrastructure-as-code/</guid><description>We started to build our own site reliability engineering team in 2016. If you are interested in learning how to plan, automate, observe and scale large platforms, you should check out our SRE group!</description></item><item><title>Connected Cars &amp; Companion Apps</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/connected-cars/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/connected-cars/</guid><description>We have been working with German car manufactures, building cloud back-ends and head unit integration for new cars coming out over the next few years. Our music streaming, mobile office and notification applications are currently running in production in data centers around the world. Also we have built a new core app (and its cloud back-ends), which is the main app for all new owners of the recently launched electric cars.</description></item><item><title>AI, Data Science &amp; Machine Learning</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/ai-data-science-machine-learning/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/ai-data-science-machine-learning/</guid><description>In our view, AI is the application of machine learning to solve a problem that previously only humans were capable of solving. We have built several decision support systems that use machine learning. One example is an AI system that employs many machine learning models together to make medical experts 10x more productive.</description></item><item><title>Flight Booking Engines</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/flight-booking-engines/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/flight-booking-engines/</guid><description>Way back in 1999, we were among the first to build travel and booking systems that connected the giant computer reservation systems (CRS) of Amadeus and Sabre to the internet. We were the first to show only the available flights, filtering out unhelpful unavailable flights, long before sites like Expedia even existed.</description></item><item><title>Online Bookstores</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/online-bookstores/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/online-bookstores/</guid><description>We have been building many of the e-commerce platforms for the competitors of Amazon in the German and European book industry. Online bookstores were quite difficult to build in the times before the cloud, because they have staggeringly large assortments, often over 20 million individual articles, which change daily. That’s a lot of data to process! On top of that it is very satisfying to work for the “underdogs” and help them to compete with industry giants like Amazon.</description></item><item><title>Companion Apps</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/companion-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/companion-apps/</guid><description>For Volkswagen we have built a new core app (and its cloud back ends), which is the main app for all new owners of the recently launched electric cars. We love using Flutter and Dart!</description></item><item><title>And There Is More</title><link>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/and-there-is-more/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-weve-build/and-there-is-more/</guid><description>We have built lottery platforms (business model: selling random numbers) and dating platforms (business model: selling contacts between customers). The internet is full of interesting new ideas and we are sure that this is still just the beginning.</description></item></channel></rss>