<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Lisboa on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/tags/lisboa/</link><description>Recent content in Lisboa on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:13:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/tags/lisboa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-11-19-hackers-wanted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:13:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-11-19-hackers-wanted/</guid><description>Recently, we started a recruiting campaign “Hackers wanted” showing that our highly educated software engineers graduated from the best universities worldwide, such as at the ISCTE Lisboa, IST Lisboa, KIT Karlsruhe, WWU Münster and the ETH Zurich.
We have a strong engineering culture. 90 % of the team are engineers with backgrounds in Computer Science, Physics or Mathematics, many also with strong Machine Learning backgrounds.
As internet pioneers, we have been building large-scale software systems since 1999, when our company was founded in Germany.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:39:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</guid><description>Hamburg/Lisbon, May 7, 2019 – The German software company freiheit.com announces the opening of a new office in Lisbon. Specialised in building large-scale software platforms, the internet pioneer works for the who-is-who of the European economy such as Mercedes Benz, Volkswagen, Engel &amp;amp; Völkers and METRO. The company is a partner of Google and has a team of 150 people of which 85 per cent are software engineers. The company’s name ‘freiheit’ means ‘freedom’ or ‘liberdade’ and expresses its mission – to take the freedom to create the future with its software.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-03-06-freiheit.com-invests-in-portugal/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 14:52:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-03-06-freiheit.com-invests-in-portugal/</guid><description>The founder and managing director of freiheit.com, Claudia Dietze, explained to BusinessIT that the company’s name means ‘freedom’ in German and is «related to open-source software which started spreading when the company was founded». The idea «was to be one of the best in the world, not the biggest».
LISBON WAS A NATURAL CHOICE Claudia revealed how they proceeded. Before leaving Germany, they investigated which places had the best universities and selected three cities: Barcelona, Madrid and Lisbon: «During four weeks, we travelled, we worked in coworking spaces, we had meetings with the founders of other companies and withthe chambers of commerce».</description></item></channel></rss>