<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>code.talks on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/tags/code.talks/</link><description>Recent content in code.talks on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 16:38:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/tags/code.talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2018-10-16-code.talks-2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 16:38:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2018-10-16-code.talks-2018/</guid><description>Some people think, that managers are not needed anymore. It is widely believed, that the future belongs to agile, self-organizing teams and emergent behavior. In a world without managers, these teams operate like some kind of swarm intelligence, that always finds the right solution, at the right time, and is constantly creating the highest value for the customer, right?
So why the hell would any sane software engineer ever consider becoming one of the grotesque characters we all know from the Dilbert comics?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-code.talks2016/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 12:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-code.talks2016/</guid><description>The code.talks&amp;nbsp;→ meanwhile is one of Europe’s biggest developer’s conference. In 2016, the developer’s bash goes into its sixth round. This time, freiheit.com is platinum sponsor and curators for track New Technology&amp;nbsp;→, Live Coding&amp;nbsp;→, and Big Data &amp;amp; Skalierung&amp;nbsp;→.
code.talks.de&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-19-codetalks_april_2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:57:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-19-codetalks_april_2016/</guid><description>Thomas Storck - CIO METRO Cash &amp;amp; Carry - knows the necessity of the digital transformation. He was the driving force behind building a food delivery software to optimize his customer’s needs. METRO is at the very top of Europe’s online retailers, counting more than 3 billion euros in revenue within the food delivery business of online orders. A strong technology partner stands behind making the first step towards the future.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015_stefan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015_stefan/</guid><description>Can we build an intelligent software agent, who portrays a perfect project manager? A bot who delivers information in the right time to the right people and who is both analyzer and messenger as well as helpful assistant at the same time? In September 2015, Stefan Richter speaks at the fifth code.talks conference about the usage of intelligent agents within software development.
Check out the presentation&amp;nbsp;→
With his presentation “Writing Simple, Readable and Robust Code: Examples in Java, Clojure and Go” Stefan Richter shows us with the help of one example three solution approaches in three different languages.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 14:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015/</guid><description>The code.talks have grown to become one of Europe’s biggest developer conferences. In 2015, the developer’s community celebrates their reunion for the fifth time. freiheit.com is gold sponsor, once again. Stefan Richter and Martin Holtschneider are curators for tracks “New Technology” and “Scalability”, respectively.
Visit code.talks.de&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 14:11:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</guid><description>Artificial neural networks have a major technological potential. Meanwhile, many open source machine learning software libraries exist in order to experiment with deep artificial neural networks, i.e. TensorFlow or Torch. In his presentation “Machine Learning mit künstlichen neuronalen Netzwerken in Clojure” (“Machine Learning with Artificial Neural Networks in Clojure”), Stefan Richter shows us - during the fourth code.talks in 2014 - how exciting it is to build one&amp;rsquo;s own library for artificial neural networks in Clojure.</description></item></channel></rss>