<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archive on freiheit.com</title>
    <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/tags/archive/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archive on freiheit.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:39:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/tags/archive/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</guid>
      <description>Hamburg/Lisbon, May 7, 2019 – The German software company freiheit.com announces the opening of a new office in Lisbon. Specialised in building large-scale software platforms, the internet pioneer works for the who-is-who of the European economy such as Mercedes Benz, Volkswagen, Engel &amp;amp; Völkers and METRO. The company is a partner of Google and has a team of 150 people of which 85 per cent are software engineers. The company’s name ‘freiheit’ means ‘freedom’ or ‘liberdade’ and expresses its mission – to take the freedom to create the future with its software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-04-29-hackertalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 15:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-04-29-hackertalks/</guid>
      <description>Our Talks cover a large variety&#xA;of topics, such as learnings from our projects, research colleagues&#xA;did in their academic work, interesting pet projects, experiences with&#xA;new technologies, and disruptive ideas. The talks are usually&#xA;presented by colleagues, but we also frequently welcome guest speakers&#xA;from diverse areas of expertise, successful startup founders, renowned&#xA;scientists and open source activists.&#xA;Unless the talks cover internal details of a customer project, they&amp;rsquo;re</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-03-06-freiheit.com-invests-in-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 14:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-03-06-freiheit.com-invests-in-portugal/</guid>
      <description>The founder and managing director of freiheit.com, Claudia Dietze, explained to BusinessIT that the company’s name means ‘freedom’ in German and is «related to open-source software which started spreading when the company was founded». The idea «was to be one of the best in the world, not the biggest».&#xA;Lisbon was a natural choice Claudia revealed how they proceeded. Before leaving Germany, they investigated which places had the best universities and selected three cities: Barcelona, Madrid and Lisbon: «During four weeks, we travelled, we worked in coworking spaces, we had meetings with the founders of other companies and withthe chambers of commerce».</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-11-01-absatzwirtschaft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 19:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-11-01-absatzwirtschaft/</guid>
      <description>Claudia Dietze speaks about the necessity of establishing detailed data of client behavior as a key to success but also respecting both privacy and informational self-determination.&#xA;Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 14:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</guid>
      <description>Artificial neural networks have a major technological potential. Meanwhile, many open source machine learning software libraries exist in order to experiment with deep artificial neural networks, i.e. TensorFlow or Torch. In his presentation “Machine Learning mit künstlichen neuronalen Netzwerken in Clojure” (“Machine Learning with Artificial Neural Networks in Clojure”), Stefan Richter shows us - during the fourth code.talks in 2014 - how exciting it is to build one&amp;rsquo;s own library for artificial neural networks in Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2010-09-24-hack_fwd_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 19:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2010-09-24-hack_fwd_2010/</guid>
      <description>Stefan Richter not only was a board member of HackFwd - a startup founded by Lars Hinrichs - but at the same time he also founded the startup project “TheDeadline”. The project made freiheit.com an early adopter of HTML5, Clojure, cloud-based NoSQL database, and smartphone clients with offline syncing. In 2010, at one of the HackFwd Build Conferences on Mallorca, Stefan explains the technical architecture of the system.&#xA;Check out his presentation&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2005-06-04-survival_of_the_fittest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2005 14:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2005-06-04-survival_of_the_fittest/</guid>
      <description>The LinuxTag is a fantastic event for programmers and free software activists. Already in 2005, Stefan has expressed interest in Objective-C and GNUstep environment. But a pet project was missing in order to learn the language. The outcome was a presentation at the LinuxTag about algorithms in Objective-C, with which Guile Scheme programs for GNU Robot could genetically be optimized.&#xA;Read the entire paper here&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
