<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Events on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/tags/events/</link><description>Recent content in Events on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 15:33:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/tags/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-04-29-hackertalks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 15:33:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-04-29-hackertalks/</guid><description>Our Talks cover a large variety
of topics, such as learnings from our projects, research colleagues
did in their academic work, interesting pet projects, experiences with
new technologies, and disruptive ideas. The talks are usually
presented by colleagues, but we also frequently welcome guest speakers
from diverse areas of expertise, successful startup founders, renowned
scientists and open source activists.
Unless the talks cover internal details of a customer project, they&amp;rsquo;re</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2018-10-16-code.talks-2018/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 16:38:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2018-10-16-code.talks-2018/</guid><description>Some people think, that managers are not needed anymore. It is widely believed, that the future belongs to agile, self-organizing teams and emergent behavior. In a world without managers, these teams operate like some kind of swarm intelligence, that always finds the right solution, at the right time, and is constantly creating the highest value for the customer, right?
So why the hell would any sane software engineer ever consider becoming one of the grotesque characters we all know from the Dilbert comics?</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-11-24-rowhow-sponsor/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-11-24-rowhow-sponsor/</guid><description>From November, 25 to 27, 2016 the third Robotic Hamburg Open Workshop (RoHOW)&amp;nbsp;→ will be held at the Hamburg University of Technology (TUHH).
The RoHOW is an educational and networking event of students of the Universität Hamburg and the TUHH with students and scientists from all over the world that are active in research on humanoid robots.
Teams of the standard platform and Humanoid Kid Size League are invited to present their work.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-10-26-mathematiker-zu-besuch/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 11:56:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-10-26-mathematiker-zu-besuch/</guid><description>On October 26, 2016, we hang out with these cool, young mathematicians from Lothar Collatz School&amp;nbsp;→ for Computing in Science, which promotes computational education &amp;amp; research at the interface of Mathematics, Computer Science, and Computational Sciences. It is a pleasure having you, thank you for visiting us!
Here´s more about the event&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-code.talks2016/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 12:08:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-code.talks2016/</guid><description>The code.talks&amp;nbsp;→ meanwhile is one of Europe’s biggest developer’s conference. In 2016, the developer’s bash goes into its sixth round. This time, freiheit.com is platinum sponsor and curators for track New Technology&amp;nbsp;→, Live Coding&amp;nbsp;→, and Big Data &amp;amp; Skalierung&amp;nbsp;→.
code.talks.de&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-fsfesummit2016/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 18:35:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-fsfesummit2016/</guid><description>Imagine the European Union builds its IT infrastructure based on free software. Imagine European member states trade information with the help of open standards and share their software. Imagine municipalities and city councils profit from decentralized and collaborative software based on free software licenses. Imagine Europeans are no longer forced to use proprietary software any longer.
That is the goal of the FSFE&amp;nbsp;→. The FSFE Summit&amp;nbsp;→ is the general assembly that unites FSFE members and supporters from all over Europe.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-openpgp206/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 11:44:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-08-24-openpgp206/</guid><description>On September 8 and September 9, 2016, the German Unix User Group in Cologne organizes the OpenPGP.conf&amp;nbsp;→ - the first public conference with main topic OpenPGP. We are supporters because strong encryption is the most important basic technology of a free and digital future society. freiheit.com is proud to support the conference as silver sponsor.
Here’s more on the conference&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-22-meetup_live_coding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 18:26:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-22-meetup_live_coding/</guid><description>Our founder Stefan Richter organizes the first Live Coding Meetup in Hamburg. On May 9, 2016, we will start off the Meetup with parser combinators in Haskell. Alex Biehl is going to present the basic concept and use of parser combinators and interactively build a JSON parser and develop a personal parser combinators library on the beamer. Parsers are used almost everywhere: HTML pages in browsers, JSON, or other small, self-defined format, which need to be assembled logically for processing, in order to be mapped onto data structures.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-19-codetalks_april_2016/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:57:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-19-codetalks_april_2016/</guid><description>Thomas Storck - CIO METRO Cash &amp;amp; Carry - knows the necessity of the digital transformation. He was the driving force behind building a food delivery software to optimize his customer’s needs. METRO is at the very top of Europe’s online retailers, counting more than 3 billion euros in revenue within the food delivery business of online orders. A strong technology partner stands behind making the first step towards the future.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-03-11-businesstalk_kirschner_fsfe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 15:29:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-03-11-businesstalk_kirschner_fsfe/</guid><description>In his talk - held on March 11, 2016 - our guest speaker Matthias Kirschner, President of the Free Software Foundation Europe (FSFE), discusses the foundation’s activity, successes, and future plans. Since October 2003, bookzilla.de is operated by freiheit.com and is the world’s first online bookstore supporting free software. All proceeds are donated to FSFE by freiheit.com since 2004. The non-profit organization supports the distribution and advancement of open source programs for over 30 years.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-10-22-online_karrieretag_2015/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 14:03:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-10-22-online_karrieretag_2015/</guid><description>On October 22, 2015, freiheit.com is a sponsor at the Online-Karrieretag in Hamburg. In his interview by Michael Karasjew (dieBewerbungsExperten.de), Stefan Richter explains what the ideal job candidate looks like.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-10-02-business_talk_lars_hinrichs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 13:53:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-10-02-business_talk_lars_hinrichs/</guid><description>On October 2, 2015, Lars Hinrichs - Internet pioneer and founder of the career network XING - is our business talk guest and speaks about his latest project: Apartimentum - a smart home located in Hamburg.
About the project&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015_stefan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015_stefan/</guid><description>Can we build an intelligent software agent, who portrays a perfect project manager? A bot who delivers information in the right time to the right people and who is both analyzer and messenger as well as helpful assistant at the same time? In September 2015, Stefan Richter speaks at the fifth code.talks conference about the usage of intelligent agents within software development.
Check out the presentation&amp;nbsp;→
With his presentation “Writing Simple, Readable and Robust Code: Examples in Java, Clojure and Go” Stefan Richter shows us with the help of one example three solution approaches in three different languages.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 14:01:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015/</guid><description>The code.talks have grown to become one of Europe’s biggest developer conferences. In 2015, the developer’s community celebrates their reunion for the fifth time. freiheit.com is gold sponsor, once again. Stefan Richter and Martin Holtschneider are curators for tracks “New Technology” and “Scalability”, respectively.
Visit code.talks.de&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-10-ecml_2015/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:51:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-09-10-ecml_2015/</guid><description>In September 2015, freiheit.com sponsors the ECML PKDD in Porto. The ECML is a machine learning conference, which takes place annually in different European locations. Our colleague Michael Großhans is a guest speaker at the conference, presenting the topic “Solving Prediction Games with Parallel Batch Gradient Descent”.
Paper and abstract&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-08-17-sylt_2015/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 19:17:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-08-17-sylt_2015/</guid><description>A day at sea with freiheit.com. It is a perfect day for a company trip to the beautiful island of Sylt, on this amazing, sunny summer’s day in the month of August, 2015. With plenty of chilled drinks and tasty food, we are spending a relaxed day, playing beach volleyball, trying ourselves at “Viking Chess”, and playing the guitar in the Western part of Kampen.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-06-16-tag_der_offenen_tuer_2015/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 13:41:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-06-16-tag_der_offenen_tuer_2015/</guid><description>Open House @ freiheit.com. On June 19, 2015, we are inviting friends and family of our colleagues to freiheit.com’s Open House, showing how exciting the work of a software engineer can be. After a tour through freiheit.com laboratories, we are inviting all of our guests to a summer BBQ on our panoramic rooftop terrace, overlooking St. Pauli.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-04-26-js_unconf_2015/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 13:35:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-04-26-js_unconf_2015/</guid><description>JS Unconf is a non-profit conference of the JavaScript community. In 2015, freiheit.com is one of the sponsors. The audience has chosen our colleague Michael Bohn to speak about “Displaying, Animating, and Comunicating with Ponies in famo.us”. Michael is providing both his presentation and demo app on our GitHub account.
Click here for the presentation&amp;nbsp;→
Check out the demo app&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-11-20-vdz_tech_summit_2014/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 14:13:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-11-20-vdz_tech_summit_2014/</guid><description>Stefan Richter holds his presentation “Von Big Data zum Machine Learning” (“From Big Data to Machine Learning”) during the second VDZ Tech Summit on November 20, 2014. His presentation illustrates how user behavior can be made transparent through data analysis and its evaluation, in order to better understand the client&amp;rsquo;s needs and for automated optimization for processes, products, and services.
Check out the interview&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 14:11:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</guid><description>Artificial neural networks have a major technological potential. Meanwhile, many open source machine learning software libraries exist in order to experiment with deep artificial neural networks, i.e. TensorFlow or Torch. In his presentation “Machine Learning mit künstlichen neuronalen Netzwerken in Clojure” (“Machine Learning with Artificial Neural Networks in Clojure”), Stefan Richter shows us - during the fourth code.talks in 2014 - how exciting it is to build one&amp;rsquo;s own library for artificial neural networks in Clojure.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2005-06-04-survival_of_the_fittest/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2005 14:05:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2005-06-04-survival_of_the_fittest/</guid><description>The LinuxTag is a fantastic event for programmers and free software activists. Already in 2005, Stefan has expressed interest in Objective-C and GNUstep environment. But a pet project was missing in order to learn the language. The outcome was a presentation at the LinuxTag about algorithms in Objective-C, with which Guile Scheme programs for GNU Robot could genetically be optimized.
Read the entire paper here&amp;nbsp;→</description></item></channel></rss>