<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Our Community on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/our-community/</link><description>Recent content in Our Community on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/our-community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Two hubs, one community</title><link>https://freiheit.com/our-community/two-hubs-one-community/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/our-community/two-hubs-one-community/</guid><description>Two hubs, one community freiheit.com was founded in Hamburg, but it has grown far beyond that. In 2018 we opened our second engineering hub in Lisbon. Our hub in Lisbon operates under the same organizational principles and team structures as our headquarters in Hamburg. The engineering members work together seamlessly and often in mixed teams between the two hubs, sharing knowledge and expertise across borders. Additionally, our members regularly travel between our engineering hubs.</description></item><item><title>Cultural Nights</title><link>https://freiheit.com/our-community/cultural-nights/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/our-community/cultural-nights/</guid><description>Cultural Nights As a cosmopolitan community, a lot of our members are not native to Germany. We regularly host cultural nights with food and drinks from their native countries – whether it’s Syria, Slavic countries, USA, Turkey or Egypt. At our most recent Portugal x Germany Cultural Night, we served Portuguese pastéis de bacalhau and German pretzels.</description></item><item><title>Board Game Nights</title><link>https://freiheit.com/our-community/board-game-nights/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/our-community/board-game-nights/</guid><description>Board Game Nights Our engineering teams love tackling complex problems. That’s why strategy games like Yggdrasil Chronicles and Mansions of Madness are the most popular at our regular board game nights in Lisbon and Hamburg.</description></item><item><title>Hackertalks</title><link>https://freiheit.com/our-community/hackertalks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/our-community/hackertalks/</guid><description>Hackertalks We are an engineering organization. 85% of our members are engineers with backgrounds in Computer Science, Physics or Mathematics, many also with strong machine learning backgrounds.
Of course we have a beautiful office in a very nice area of each city. But more important is that self-Improvement and learning are deeply ingrained into our company&amp;rsquo;s DNA and in the personality of all of our team members. We tackle new and interesting problems all the time and very often create things that nobody has built before.</description></item><item><title>Sports: Running, Biking, Bouldering, Soccer and More</title><link>https://freiheit.com/our-community/sports/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/our-community/sports/</guid><description>Sports: Running, Biking, Bouldering, Soccer and More If you can name a sport, there’s probably freiheit.com members who like it. We have several groups who organize regular bike trips, play soccer or even train for and run the yearly Haspa Marathon in Hamburg. Multiple times a month our members organize a yoga session in our office.</description></item></channel></rss>