<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Press on freiheit.com</title><link>https://freiheit.com/tags/press/</link><description>Recent content in Press on freiheit.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:13:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://freiheit.com/tags/press/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-11-19-hackers-wanted/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:13:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-11-19-hackers-wanted/</guid><description>Recently, we started a recruiting campaign “Hackers wanted” showing that our highly educated software engineers graduated from the best universities worldwide, such as at the ISCTE Lisboa, IST Lisboa, KIT Karlsruhe, WWU Münster and the ETH Zurich.
We have a strong engineering culture. 90 % of the team are engineers with backgrounds in Computer Science, Physics or Mathematics, many also with strong Machine Learning backgrounds.
As internet pioneers, we have been building large-scale software systems since 1999, when our company was founded in Germany.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:39:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</guid><description>Hamburg/Lisbon, May 7, 2019 – The German software company freiheit.com announces the opening of a new office in Lisbon. Specialised in building large-scale software platforms, the internet pioneer works for the who-is-who of the European economy such as Mercedes Benz, Volkswagen, Engel &amp;amp; Völkers and METRO. The company is a partner of Google and has a team of 150 people of which 85 per cent are software engineers. The company’s name ‘freiheit’ means ‘freedom’ or ‘liberdade’ and expresses its mission – to take the freedom to create the future with its software.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-06-02-aubrey_de_grey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 12:38:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-06-02-aubrey_de_grey/</guid><description>On June 2, 2017, we got an awesome guest speaker at our HackerTalk - Aubrey de Grey&amp;nbsp;→, the Chief Science Officer and Co-Founder of the SENS Research Foundation&amp;nbsp;→. The foundation&amp;rsquo;s stated goal is to transform the way the world researches and treats age-related disease. Aubrey provocatively proposes that the first human beings who will live to 1,000 years old have already been born.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-05-05-marco_boerries_hackertalk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 14:28:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-05-05-marco_boerries_hackertalk/</guid><description>On May 5, 2017, Marco Börries&amp;nbsp;→ presents his fourth product, NumberFour, or recently branded as enfore&amp;nbsp;→. Marco Börries is a German software engineer, a business friend and partner - and passionate entrepreneur!
In his talk „Make small business work in a complex world“, he gives us an insight into his current product, his strategy as well as the architecture and technologies.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-03-23-spiegel_online_buero_fdc/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 14:57:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-03-23-spiegel_online_buero_fdc/</guid><description>SPIEGEL ONLINE compares the top 17 offices worldwide - we are in. According to a study, the productivity of each individual depends on the spatiality of the workplace. Where would you like to work?
Check it out at SPIEGEL ONLINE&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-03-03-video_cmagnussen/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 17:19:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-03-03-video_cmagnussen/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="why-being-scared-of-machine-learning-will-leave-you-in-the-90s">Why being scared of Machine Learning will leave you in the 90s&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a class="font-serif no-underline hover:text-red" href="http://christophmagnussen.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Christoph Magnussen&amp;nbsp;→&lt;/a> and Stefan Richter met for a quick talk about the fear of many companies to utilize their data and the state of security when using cloud. Hope it&amp;rsquo;s useful to you guys!&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/76gs8VC7c2M" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video">&lt;/iframe>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-01-20-huffington-post/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 11:43:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2017-01-20-huffington-post/</guid><description>Die Maschine bekommt ein sympathisches Gesicht&amp;nbsp;→, nämlich unseres&amp;nbsp;→
Even though machines are taking over more jobs that previously have been executed by humans, this development also bears a lot of opportunities for us, because we are still a valuable workforce. Nevertheless, the population declines and becomes increasingly older and many exciting jobs still remain that only someone made out of flesh and blood can do best. At the same time, the human workforce is decreasing.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-09-22-saalzwei_sep16/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 21:01:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-09-22-saalzwei_sep16/</guid><description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive.
Today: Man muss kein Programmierer sein&amp;nbsp;→, um Software zu entwickeln&amp;nbsp;→.
Not so long ago, not many job positions were offered for non-engineers in the digital industry. This has changed immensely. More and more jobs are created, where even a university degree in archaeology, history, or philosophy will take you a long way in the digital industry.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-05-12-office_snapshots/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-05-12-office_snapshots/</guid><description>The photo blog “Office Snapshots” shows inspiring office designs from all over the globe. Along our company ethos “design follows function”, we have created a place, where both creative and analytical teams are able to ideally work in an innovative atmosphere. Office Snapshots has now published our work space among “the world’s best office designs” …
Check out Office Snapshots&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-26-saalzwei_recruiting/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 14:16:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-26-saalzwei_recruiting/</guid><description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive.
In the digital age, recruiting is becoming the most important management role, which is not only executed by CEOs in Silicon Valley. In her column “Jobinterviews sind CEO-Sache”, Claudia explains the importance of a CEO’s presence and how to implement a corporate value system in today’s recruiting process.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-01-wiwo_chefbueros/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 15:29:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2016-04-01-wiwo_chefbueros/</guid><description>The slideshow in the series “Chefbüro” of the German magazine “WirtschaftsWoche” (14/2016), offers us a glimpse into the offices of the best managers. Throughout the three open-spaced, modern floors of the software company freiheit.com, located in the vibrant borough St. Pauli, Claudia shows how freiheit.com’s hacker culture comes to life in the office: “German Engineering meets Silicon Valley”. The mechanical model ship displayed on Claudia’s sideboard is a gift given to her by the late NASA pioneer Prof.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-12-04-zeit_online_dez15/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 19:23:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-12-04-zeit_online_dez15/</guid><description>In her interview with ZEIT ONLINE, Claudia Dietze explains why authority and responsibility need ownership, not hierarchy.
Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-10-15-saalzwei_wer_braucht_manager/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 18:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-10-15-saalzwei_wer_braucht_manager/</guid><description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive. In her column titled “Wer braucht heute noch Manager?” (“Who still needs managers today?”), Claudia explains how new management concepts, such as Holacracy, leads towards meaningful tasks and better results.
Wer braucht heute noch Manager?&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-08-01-claudia_charmante_mrs_perfect/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 13:56:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-08-01-claudia_charmante_mrs_perfect/</guid><description>In the newspaper series of the Hamburger Abendblatt “Der Rote Faden” (“The Red Thread”), which symbolizes a connection between people who respect and appreciate each other. XING founder Lars Hinrichs has extended the red thread to Claudia Dietze. In the following article, entrepreneur Claudia Dietze explains why to her reason and passion are not contrary to one another.
Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-07-01-saalzwei_maker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 18:03:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-07-01-saalzwei_maker/</guid><description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive.
Makers determine a company’s future - why? Claudia provides an answer in her column “Sind Sie ein &amp;lsquo;Maker&amp;rsquo; oder verwalten Sie?” (“Are you a ‘maker’ or are you an administrator?”).
Sind Sie ein &amp;lsquo;Maker&amp;rsquo; oder verwalten Sie?&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-06-10-perfect_the_enemy_of_good/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 19:14:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2015-06-10-perfect_the_enemy_of_good/</guid><description>manager magazin - a German monthly magazine focusing on business, finance and management - publishes a collection of the best advices given in the SAAL ZWEI interview series “3 FRAGEN AN 30 FRAUEN.” (“3 QUESTIONS FOR 30 WOMEN.”). Amongst them, Claudia Dietze’s SAAL ZWEI column “Perfect is the enemy of good” has also been selected.
Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-12-17-saal_zwei_2014/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 19:08:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-12-17-saal_zwei_2014/</guid><description>In the SAAL ZWEI column “3 QUESTIONS FOR 30 WOMEN.” the online magazine introduces 30 female top managers, who are all game changers in their industries. Among them is Claudia Dietze, who is convinced that most of the time perfect is the enemy of good. Along this corporate principle and for more than 15 years, she has been successfully leading her company towards the future.
Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-11-01-absatzwirtschaft/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 19:05:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-11-01-absatzwirtschaft/</guid><description>Claudia Dietze speaks about the necessity of establishing detailed data of client behavior as a key to success but also respecting both privacy and informational self-determination.
Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description></item><item><title/><link>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-06-06-wir_haben_eine_hackerkultur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 13:58:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://freiheit.com/what-others-say/2014-06-06-wir_haben_eine_hackerkultur/</guid><description>Claudia Dietze speaks of the necessity of transferring standard business models into the digital world and, furthermore, about freiheit.com’s hacker culture. freiheit.com is one of 900.000 mid-sized business customers of Deutsche Bank.
Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description></item></channel></rss>