<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Who We are on freiheit.com</title>
    <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Who We are on freiheit.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 14:05:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Merry Christmas</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/xmas/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/xmas/1/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp; MERRY CHRISTMAS AND A HAPPY NEW YEAR! FELIZ NATAL E UM PRÓSPERO ANO NOVA! In 2024, our engineers wrote 7,797,336 lines of code, completed 18,923 user stories and made over 62,500 commits. What a year.&#xA;As we always say, technology and engineering never rest.&#xA;This year, another big engineering milestone was hit. The first successful mid-air catch of the Super Heavy booster was accomplished, marking a breakthrough in rocket reusability and reducing turnaround times for launches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two hubs, one community </title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/two-hubs-one-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/two-hubs-one-community/</guid>
      <description>Two hubs, one community freiheit.com was founded in Hamburg, but it has grown far beyond that. In 2018 we opened our second engineering hub in Lisbon.&#xA;Our hub in Lisbon operates under the same organizational principles and team structures as our headquarters in Hamburg. The engineering members work together seamlessly and often in mixed teams between the two hubs, sharing knowledge and expertise across borders.&#xA;Additionally, our members regularly travel between our engineering hubs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are a global team</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/join-us/our-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/join-us/our-community/</guid>
      <description>We are a global team. In our Engineering Hubs in Hamburg and Lisbon you will meet people from all over the world, different cultures, colors, languages, genders and lifestyles. We celebrate diversity and openness.&#xA;When you ask anybody why they are working here, it is pretty likely that people will say “because of the people” and “because I have never learnt so much in my life”. Our company is a place to be yourself, aim high, taking care of each other and growing without limits.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/imprint/force-css/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/imprint/force-css/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Follow us</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/get-in-touch/contact-followus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/get-in-touch/contact-followus/</guid>
      <description>Follow us YouTube&amp;nbsp;→&#xA;LinkedIn&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode one</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-01/</guid>
      <description>In his early twenties, Greg started as a Stanford Grad at Google, went through the famous APM program and then went on as one of the early engineers at Instagram, He was there when Facebook acquired it. Now he is living in NYC and we will talk about the life of a product manager and software engineer in Silicon Valley.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to make your systems highly available and fast</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-16-why-agile-is-not-enough-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-16-why-agile-is-not-enough-01/</guid>
      <description>What have we learned in building our own SRE organization over the last five years?&#xA;What are the most important first steps when building up a strong SRE organization?&#xA;How can you transform your operations staff into a powerful SRE team?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our ways of working</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/infrastructure-modernization-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/infrastructure-modernization-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</guid>
      <description>Our ways of working In small, cross-functional teams, we have been building successful software products for digital business models iteratively and data-driven for over 26 years. Each Team includes a Team Lead, who is a software engineer thyself and writes code every day. Team Leads are also usually trained as Product Owners and are appreciated as contacts for the Product Owner on the client side. A Site Reliability Engineer works with each team to automate all development and operational processes and establishes effective monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culture nights</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/culture-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/culture-nights/</guid>
      <description>Culture nights Because there are so many nations present within the freiheit.com community, we host culture nights.&#xA;Each month one or a group of members presents their culture - cook their traditional food, show their traditional music and tell us about their traditional customs. Our members baked Polish pastries, taught the others Egyptian dances, made Indian samosas, gave the best French wine tasting… the list goes on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our ways of working</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-ways-of-working/</guid>
      <description>Our ways of working In small, cross-functional teams, we have been building successful software products for digital business models iteratively and data-driven for over 26 years. Each Team includes a Team Lead, who is a software engineer themself and writes code every day. Team Leads are also usually trained as Product Owners and are appreciated as contacts for the Product Owner on the client side. A Site Reliability Engineer works with each team to automate all development and operational processes and establishes effective monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hamburg</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/get-in-touch/contact-hamburg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/get-in-touch/contact-hamburg/</guid>
      <description>Hamburg Budapester Str. 45&#xA;20359 Hamburg&#xA;Germany</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode two</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-02/</guid>
      <description>From Product Manager at Google to CEO at Lever: Stefan Richter talked with Sarah Nahm. After working as a product manager at Google, she founded Lever, a company that changed recruiting worldwide. Sarah will tell us her story and how the Associate Product Management Program (APM) at Google helped her to become a CEO of her own company.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to build and run an efficient software engineering organization</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-16-why-agile-is-not-enough-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-16-why-agile-is-not-enough-02/</guid>
      <description>Running a software project is still hard and a lot of companies still struggle to make their teams efficient, productive and successful. As many companies have already noticed, working “agile” is also not the silver bullet.&#xA;Stefan Richter, Founder and Head of Engineering of freiheit.com, shares his insights on how to empower teams to manage themselves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure modernization from start to end</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/infrastructure-modernization-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/infrastructure-modernization-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</guid>
      <description>Infrastructure modernization from start to end To understand the client’s requirements and goals and align our ways of working, we set up a series of workshops with our new clients covering:&#xA;- Different business cases&#xA;- Looking at complete customer user journeys&#xA;- Demonstrating possible solutions&#xA;- Setting up initial prioritized and estimated backlogs based on MoSCoW method&#xA;Our self built tool Revolution enables the teams to work autonomously and create reproducible results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our public customer success stories</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/infrastructure-modernization-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/infrastructure-modernization-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</guid>
      <description>Our public customer success stories Using the Google Cloud Platform, we successfully migrated many of our clients to the cloud. With two of them we have published success stories to which you can find more information below. Many more are to come.&#xA;Hornbach freiheit.com’s mission was to roll out Anthos, including the migration of existing network policies, implementing continuous integration/deployment, debugging Istio and network issues, and ensuring a successful and smooth project implementation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Board game nights</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/board-game-nights/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/board-game-nights/</guid>
      <description>Board game nights Our engineering teams love tackling complex problems. That’s why strategy games like Yggdrasil Chronicles and Mansions of Madness are the most popular at our regular board game nights in Lisbon and Hamburg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Application development from start to end</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/application-development-from-start-to-end/</guid>
      <description>Application development from start to end To understand the client’s requirements and goals and align our ways of working, we set up a series of workshops with our new clients covering:&#xA;- Different business cases&#xA;- Looking at complete customer user journeys&#xA;- Demonstrating possible solutions&#xA;- Setting up initial prioritized and estimated backlogs based on MoSCoW method&#xA;Our self built tool Revolution enables the teams to work autonomously and create reproducible results.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our public customer success stories</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/application-development-for-the-google-cloud-platform/our-public-customer-success-stories-with-metro-and-tchibo/</guid>
      <description>Our public customer success stories Using the Google Cloud Platform, we successfully migrated many of our clients to the cloud. With two of them we have published success stories to which you can find more information below. Many more are to come.&#xA;Hyper-Scalable E-Commerce System We helped the coffee house and seasonal retailer Tchibo to revolutionize its multinational e-commerce website. Going from on-premises to Google Cloud Platform&amp;nbsp;→ relieved the company’s IT-professionals and made it possible to break down the system’s monolithic core into microservices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lisbon</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/get-in-touch/contact-lisbon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/get-in-touch/contact-lisbon/</guid>
      <description>Lisbon Edificio Heden Rossio&#xA;Largo do Duque de Cadaval 17 Fracção I&#xA;1200-160 Lisbon&#xA;Portugal</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode three</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-03/</guid>
      <description>How METRO moved into the cloud, created a billion-euro global business platform and reinvented their IT organization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How To Optimize Engineering Productivity</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-16-why-agile-is-not-enough-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-16-why-agile-is-not-enough-03/</guid>
      <description>Stefan Richter, Founder &amp;amp; Head of Engineering @ freiheit.com, talks about engineering productivity: a data-driven engineering discipline focused on optimizing the engineering process so that organizations can deliver amazing experiences to their users faster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hackertalks</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/hackertalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/hackertalks/</guid>
      <description>Hackertalks Every Friday, our engineering members organize a Hackertalk.&#xA;We are an engineering organization. 85% of our members are engineers with backgrounds in Computer Science, Physics or Mathematics, many also with strong machine learning backgrounds. We tackle new and interesting problems all the time and very often create things that nobody has built before.&#xA;That’s why our freiheit.com engineers meet for Hackertalks every Friday. Some members enjoy a drink afterward in our community area on the 6th floor, overlooking the port of Hamburg.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode four</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-04/</guid>
      <description>Sven Lipowski and Stefan Richter started METRO’s first digital transformation project in 2015. He shares their insights on how they started METRO’s biggest digitization project together, from the first workshop until making €4 billion turnover per year with a highly scalable microservice platform running in 24 countries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode five</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-05/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-05/</guid>
      <description>Frerk Lätari and Stefan Richter share their key challenges and insights on how to do a successful lift &amp;amp; shift into the Google Cloud of one of Germany’s largest e-commerce systems within three months.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sports: running, biking, bouldering, soccer and more</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/our-community/sports/</guid>
      <description>Sports: running, biking, bouldering, soccer and more If you can name a sport, there’s probably freiheit.com members who like it. We have several groups who organize regular bike trips, play soccer or even train for and run the yearly Haspa Marathon in Hamburg. Multiple times a month our members organize a yoga session in our office.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode six</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-06/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-06/</guid>
      <description>After studying logistics &amp;amp; e-business in Remagen and playing bass in jazz clubs at night for a living, Sascha became a management consultant after he earned his first product management chops in the telco industry. Then he became a founding member of the product team at MOIA and launched this new kind of mobility service in Hamburg in 2019. He will share a good amount of war stories from this amazing journey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode seven</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-07/</guid>
      <description>Jackie Bavaro started her career as a PM at Microsoft and Google. At Google, Jackie was part of the famous APM program and worked as a Product Manager for the Google Data APIs and Google Search. In 2011, Jackie joined Asana as the company’s first Product Manager before she later became the Head of Product Management. Jackie is also the co-author of the famous book “Cracking the PM Interview: How to Land a Product Manager Job in Technology”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Episode eight</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2021-08-17-humans-in-tech-episode-08/</guid>
      <description>In the last five years, Christoph Magnussen, book author, filmmaker, keynote speaker and CEO of Blackboat, produced more than 300 podcast episodes about New Work. In the House of New Work in Hamburg, he rethinks the standards of how knowledge workers will collaborate in the 21st century. How did he get to this point, and what were his key learnings along the way?&#xA;Click here to see part 1&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/welcome/</guid>
      <description> Building Large-Scale Software Systems Since 1999 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We make the impossible possible</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-make-the-impossible-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-make-the-impossible-possible/</guid>
      <description>We make the impossible possible. We are a software engineering company by engineers for engineers.&#xA;For over a quarter of a century we have been building large-scale software systems that are business-critical to our clients.&#xA;Large-scale means millions of users, queries, transactions and billions of revenue.&#xA;We deliver fast and in daily increments to always deliver on time, on target, on budget and on quality.&#xA;We are building scalable systems that can be used, extended and maintained for decades to come.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are efficient and successful</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-efficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-efficient/</guid>
      <description>We are efficient and successful. Our teams work data-driven to constantly optimize their own productivity by removing friction from their work.&#xA;We have capable people on every level of our engineering organization.&#xA;Nothing that is of any value can be accomplished without dedication and hard work. This is why we give the best we can in any situation.&#xA;Technology never rests. And neither do we.&#xA;85% of our members are engineers with backgrounds in computer science, physics, mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are pioneers</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-pioneers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-pioneers/</guid>
      <description>We are pioneers. freiheit.com technologies was founded in 1999 in the midst of the first internet boom.&#xA;Since then, we’ve been building custom, large-scale software platforms and helping our clients to create their future business models based on software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are software engineers</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-software-engineers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-software-engineers/</guid>
      <description>We are software engineers. We see software development as an engineering discipline. We focus on simplicity, lean and iterative engineering – and fast delivery processes since our foundation and long before “agile” became a buzzword.&#xA;Good software engineering means “keeping it simple”. We are building the simplest “software machine” with as few parts, mechanisms and dependencies as possible.&#xA;Simple does not mean easy.&#xA;Working at freiheit.com is an exciting adventure, with the goal to become a well-rounded software engineer who is able to plan, create, operate and lead large-scale systems in a team of software engineers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We are problem solvers</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-problem-solvers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-are-problem-solvers/</guid>
      <description>We are problem solvers. We love taking on difficult and ambitious missions and solving challenging problems. We believe that nothing is impossible.&#xA;We combine a growth mindset with long-term thinking and a can-do won’t stop attitude.&#xA;We are known for our deep technical expertise and our track record of delivering successful software projects. In over two decades, we have never failed to deliver what we promised.&#xA;This is why our clients entrust us with their most important projects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We all have the same mission</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-have-all-the-same-mission/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/we-have-all-the-same-mission/</guid>
      <description>We all have the same mission. It all started in a kitchen in 1999 with our two founders. Now we are 250+ people in Hamburg and Lisbon.&#xA;Both of our hubs operate under the same organizational principals and team structure. Our teams work together seamlessly, sharing knowledge and expertise across borders.&#xA;We are one community&amp;nbsp;→&#xA;No matter how many of us there are. To our core, we have always stayed the same.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Collective intelligence and intelligent collective</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/collective-intelligence-and-intelligent-collective/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/collective-intelligence-and-intelligent-collective/</guid>
      <description>Collective intelligence and intelligent collective. As engineers, we strive to distribute our knowledge and best practices to everyone within our company. Our goal is to make sure all team members “know what the company knows.” This reduces our reliance on individual experts and also helps us avoid making the same mistakes twice.&#xA;To keep our expertise up to date, we have a lean and fast request for comments process, where all team members contribute to our knowledge base.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-12-01-we-support-the-speyer-cathedral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 14:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-12-01-we-support-the-speyer-cathedral/</guid>
      <description>The Speyer Cathedral The almost one thousand year old Speyer Cathedral stands as a testament to the ambitions of many great German emperors and kings. Amongst them Conrad II, Henry IV and Henry V.&#xA;This long-standing beauty, consecrated in 1061 and known as the largest surviving Romanesque church in the world, was captured by Horst Hamann in 2024.&#xA;The German photographer shows us a new perspective of the monument through his characteristic vertical photography style on over 190 pages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-11-13-product-and-systems-engineering-leads/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-11-13-product-and-systems-engineering-leads/</guid>
      <description>We are a software engineering company - by engineers for engineers. How are we successfully delivering large-scale projects to our clients always on time, on budget, on target and on quality? To deliver the right product, we need to understand the client’s needs, establish the project scope and define the right features. We always ensure that we maintain uniformity and simplicity within the code base throughout the project. Who is responsible for that?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-11-13-the-attributes-series/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-11-13-the-attributes-series/</guid>
      <description>At freiheit.com we hire only top ranking students. But we know that performance is not only built on skills that are visible to us, that we learned and trained, like coding skills. Instead, performance also builds on hidden qualities that tell us how we show up when things get hard, in situations of stress, challenge or uncertainty. We call them Attributes. They are inherent to our nature and therefore harder but not impossible to develop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-10-16-lisbon-summer-event-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-10-16-lisbon-summer-event-2024/</guid>
      <description>September was special for our Lisbon engineering hub — it was our first-ever beach Summer Event. We had an amazing time surfing, playing beach volleyball and having great talks about technology and engineering.&#xA;It was all about having good discussions, lots of fun and creating new memories.&#xA;Our Lisbon hub has come a long way since its start in 2018 when our&#xA;co-founder Claudia Dietze made her dream come true by opening a second hub for freiheit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-08-07-california-night-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-08-07-california-night-2024/</guid>
      <description>This years motto: it’s all about California 🎉&#xA;Our founders Claudia Dietze and Stefan Richter fell in love with California a long time ago and like to bring the spirit back to Germany. 🌴&#xA;Events like this are always a good occasion for all of us to get to know each other more, for senior members to meet the newbies and for everyone to enjoy time and talk about old stories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the fastest beauty mobile shop in the industry for 80&#43; countries</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/building-the-fastest-beauty-mobile-shop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/building-the-fastest-beauty-mobile-shop/</guid>
      <description>We helped cosnova bring best-in-class user experience to their customers by rebuilding the two webshops for their brands Catrice and essence, delivering on a tight deadline. The webpages were rolled out in over 80 countries worldwide and provide high performance using the Next JS framework. The page scored &amp;ldquo;green&amp;rdquo; on Google&amp;rsquo;s Lighthouse test, indicating low page load times and a short time to be interactive for the page’s users. We rebuilt the UI Component Library using React and (S)CSS to optimize the user experience on both webshops across multiple devices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-07-02-mein-nachfolger-ist-eine-ki/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-07-02-mein-nachfolger-ist-eine-ki/</guid>
      <description>Download PDF&amp;nbsp;→&#xA;Jeder, der selbst ein Unternehmen gegründet und groß gemacht hat, weiß etwas, was andere nicht wissen, und macht Dinge, die andere nicht machen. Darum war das Unternehmen erfolgreich. Wie kann KI helfen, dieses implizite Wissen an die Nachfolgegeneration zu übertragen?&#xA;Ich habe 1983 mein erstes Computerprogramm geschrieben. Zwei Hochschulabschlüsse in Informatik und Systemanalyse später habe ich zusammen mit meiner Co-Gründerin Claudia Dietze vor über einem Vierteljahrhundert meine eigene Softwarefirma freiheit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-06-25-freiheit-com-at-stackit-cloud-x-summit-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-06-25-freiheit-com-at-stackit-cloud-x-summit-2024/</guid>
      <description>STACKIT is developing an entire German business cloud. freiheit.com works for and with the Schwarz IT on various internal software products and is also involved in the development of the STACKIT platform. This is a gigantic task.&#xA;How can software engineering be made more effective, efficient and successful?&#xA;We at freiheit.com believe it&amp;rsquo;s through data-driven software engineering.&#xA;That is what our Head of Engineering and Co-Founder, Stefan Richter talked about at the STACKIT Cloud x Summit yesterday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Global B2B Retail Platform</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/global-b2b-retail-platform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/global-b2b-retail-platform/</guid>
      <description>For the food giant METRO we have built a large-scale e-commerce platform and rolled it out to 20+ countries. After just under five years, the system now generates over 4 billion euros per year and has become one of the largest Google Cloud&amp;nbsp;→ customers in Europe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cloud-Based Mobile Inventory Management for EDEKA</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/cloud-based-mobile-inventory-management-for-edeka/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/cloud-based-mobile-inventory-management-for-edeka/</guid>
      <description>Over 30 months, four teams developed a flutter-based solution connected to an Azure backend in the cloud, that is currently used by more than 200 stores of EDEKA – the largest German supermarket corporation. More retail stores from the EDEKA group are to follow.&#xA;Together with EDEKA DIGITAL, the IT subsidiary of EDEKA headquarters, we designed and implemented a new mobile inventory management solution (Warenwirtschaftssystem) to support all processes in their supermarkets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connected Cloud Services for Dentsply Sirona</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/connected-cloud-services-dentsply-sirona/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/connected-cloud-services-dentsply-sirona/</guid>
      <description>With one of the world’s largest manufacturers of professional dental products and technologies, we have built a cloud ecosystem that lets dentists collect and process 3D image data in the cloud right from their scanning device. The service enables real-time cloud collaboration between specialists and ordering 3D printed oral appliances with strict GDPR compliance. This first-of-its-kind solution not only gives our client a competitive advantage, but also streamlines healthcare services for millions of patients around the globe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using Machine Learning Algorithms to Fulfill Physical Order Slips for BA.Unternehmensgruppe</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/ai-data-science-machine-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/ai-data-science-machine-learning/</guid>
      <description>To relieve workload from skilled professionals, our engineers set out to make the processing of physical order slips 10x more efficient. They built a system that processes complex image data to extract and categorize information using machine learning algorithms. This significantly reduced workload from specialists and freed up time for more demanding tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connected Cars &amp; Companion Apps</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/connected-cars/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/connected-cars/</guid>
      <description>We have been working with German car manufactures, building cloud back-ends and head unit integration for new cars coming out over the next few years. Our music streaming, mobile office and notification applications are currently running in production in data centers around the world. Also we have built a new core app (and its cloud back-ends), which is the main app for all new owners of the recently launched electric cars.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the Backbone of Tchibo’s digital Business</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/hyper-scalable-e-commerce-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/hyper-scalable-e-commerce-system/</guid>
      <description>In 2009 we built a new custom webshop for Tchibo, a leading coffee and consumer goods retailer in Europe with an annual turnover of €3 billion.&#xA;“Jede Woche eine neue Welt” – Tchibo’s unique concept required a webshop as dynamic as their vision. Their former standardized webshop solution couldn’t keep up with growing webshop sales at that time. So we rebuilt their whole system from scratch.&#xA;We committed the Go-Live date for the new webshop twelve months in advance – and delivered as planned and on time, on budget, on target.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Site Reliability Engineering &amp; Infrastructure as Code</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/site-reliability-engineering-infrastructure-as-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/site-reliability-engineering-infrastructure-as-code/</guid>
      <description>We started to build our own site reliability engineering team in 2016. If you are interested in learning how to plan, automate, observe and scale large platforms, you should check out our SRE group!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building the future of Omnichannel Retail Platforms</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/building-the-future-of-omnichannel-retail-platforms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/building-the-future-of-omnichannel-retail-platforms/</guid>
      <description>freiheit.com enabled Peek &amp;amp; Cloppenburg Düsseldorf to create a seamless omnichannel platform using Google Cloud&amp;nbsp;→. With 160 stores in 16 countries and multiple international online shops, Peek &amp;amp; Cloppenburg Düsseldorf fashion group sells high-grade fashion for all ages. Together with P&amp;amp;C, we built a scalable system for personalized shopping experiences based on customer interests and purchase history. The retail platform drives sales performance by connecting online and in-store shopping experiences.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flight Booking Engines</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/flight-booking-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/flight-booking-engines/</guid>
      <description>Way back in 1999, we were among the first to build travel and booking systems that connected the giant computer reservation systems (CRS) of Amadeus and Sabre to the internet. We were the first to show only the available flights, filtering out unhelpful unavailable flights, long before sites like Expedia even existed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online Bookstores</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/online-bookstores/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/online-bookstores/</guid>
      <description>We have been building many of the e-commerce platforms for the competitors of Amazon in the German and European book industry. Online bookstores were quite difficult to build in the times before the cloud, because they have staggeringly large assortments, often over 20 million individual articles, which change daily. That’s a lot of data to process! On top of that it is very satisfying to work for the “underdogs” and help them to compete with industry giants like Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-04-10-a-life-changing-moment/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-04-10-a-life-changing-moment/</guid>
      <description>Do you remember a life-changing moment for you? This is mine.&#xA;After 25 years of building and running my company freiheit.com technologies, which I co-founded together with Stefan Richter, as I planned two years ago I am handing over my role as CEO.&#xA;Stefan started as the first software engineer and employee no. 1 in October 1998, and in February 1999 we incorporated our company together.&#xA;I took over the business part, and he took over the engineering part.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-04-08-case-study-dentsply-sirona/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2024-04-08-case-study-dentsply-sirona/</guid>
      <description>Dentsply Sirona had a vision. To make the workflow of dental practices around the world efficient, fast and seamless. To give dentists time to focus on what’s really important, the well-being of the patients.&#xA;Available worldwide. For 100.000+ dentists. With millions of dental procedures every day. To make this vision come to life, Dentsply Sirona was looking for a strong partner to help them build a solution that would bring all the dental applications safely into the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2023-11-29-bundesweiter-it-fachkraeftemangel/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 17:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2023-11-29-bundesweiter-it-fachkraeftemangel/</guid>
      <description>Bundesweit fehlen rund 68.000 IT-Experten*. Trotzdem gelingt es freiheit.com die Top-5-Prozent der Uni-Absolventen zu finden und für sich zu gewinnen. Tatsächlich stellt freiheit.com nur 2,5 Prozent der Bewerber ein. Das Team aus über 200 Spezialisten baut seit 25 Jahren large-scale Software-Systeme für internationale Unternehmen verschiedener Branchen. Wie gelingt es freiheit.com, in für das Recruiting schwierigen Zeiten die besten Talente auf dem Arbeitsmarkt zu finden, zu rekrutieren und zu halten?&#xA;Ein Software-Unternehmen von &amp;ldquo;Engineers for Engineers&amp;rdquo; freiheit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2023-09-05-bis-zu-50-prozent-aller-it-projekte/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2023 17:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2023-09-05-bis-zu-50-prozent-aller-it-projekte/</guid>
      <description>freiheit.com zählt zu den führenden Software-Unternehmen in Europa. Das Team aus über 200 Software-Engineers baut seit fast einem Vierteljahrhundert &amp;ldquo;large-scale Software Platforms&amp;rdquo;, große strategische Systeme für internationale Unternehmen mit Millionen von Nutzern und Transaktionen. So können für freiheit.com&amp;rsquo;s Kunden Wettbewerbsvorteile und neue, globale Geschäftsmodelle realisiert werden.&#xA;freiheit.com hat seit 1999 über 350 large-scale Software-Projekte erfolgreich abgeschlossen - immer innerhalb der vereinbarten Zeit und des vereinbarten Kostenrahmens. Die Projekte von freiheit.com ermöglichen den Kunden ihre Umsätze in strategisch wichtigen Bereichen zu steigern oder die Effizienz signifikant zu erhöhen PMI-Studie zeigt: 50 Prozent aller IT-Projekte weltweit überschreiten die Deadline.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2020-02-06-portugal-is-a-perfect-place-to-create-businesses-for-the-digital-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 17:03:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2020-02-06-portugal-is-a-perfect-place-to-create-businesses-for-the-digital-future/</guid>
      <description>You and your partner Stefan Richter took a big risk in starting your own tech company from scratch. What led you to it? We didn’t see it as a risk. We still see it as an adventure. We wanted to create the company we had always looked for. A company that is more a community of highly educated, intelligent and ambitious people working in an unconventional way without vanity and politics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-12-20-freiheit.com-supports-the-heroes-of-the-sea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 17:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-12-20-freiheit.com-supports-the-heroes-of-the-sea/</guid>
      <description>Hamburg/Lisbon, December 10, 2019 – The German software company freiheit.com has allocated a donation to the actual environmental project of York Hovest. Together with two friends, the photographer and National Geographic book author will cross the Atlantic Ocean in a rowboat – from Gran Canaria to Barbados during a period of over 50 days. York started this journey just ten days ago. The ocean crossing is part of his mission to save the oceans by enhancing the visibility of the “Heroes of the Sea” as he calls the people in his recent book whose activities contribute to saving the oceans.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-11-19-hackers-wanted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 17:13:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-11-19-hackers-wanted/</guid>
      <description>Recently, we started a recruiting campaign “Hackers wanted” showing that our highly educated software engineers graduated from the best universities worldwide, such as at the ISCTE Lisboa, IST Lisboa, KIT Karlsruhe, WWU Münster and the ETH Zurich.&#xA;We have a strong engineering culture. 90 % of the team are engineers with backgrounds in Computer Science, Physics or Mathematics, many also with strong Machine Learning backgrounds.&#xA;As internet pioneers, we have been building large-scale software systems since 1999, when our company was founded in Germany.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 16:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-05-13-press-article-lisboa/</guid>
      <description>Hamburg/Lisbon, May 7, 2019 – The German software company freiheit.com announces the opening of a new office in Lisbon. Specialised in building large-scale software platforms, the internet pioneer works for the who-is-who of the European economy such as Mercedes Benz, Volkswagen, Engel &amp;amp; Völkers and METRO. The company is a partner of Google and has a team of 150 people of which 85 per cent are software engineers. The company’s name ‘freiheit’ means ‘freedom’ or ‘liberdade’ and expresses its mission – to take the freedom to create the future with its software.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-04-29-hackertalks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 15:33:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-04-29-hackertalks/</guid>
      <description>Our Talks cover a large variety&#xA;of topics, such as learnings from our projects, research colleagues&#xA;did in their academic work, interesting pet projects, experiences with&#xA;new technologies, and disruptive ideas. The talks are usually&#xA;presented by colleagues, but we also frequently welcome guest speakers&#xA;from diverse areas of expertise, successful startup founders, renowned&#xA;scientists and open source activists.&#xA;Unless the talks cover internal details of a customer project, they&amp;rsquo;re</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-03-06-freiheit.com-invests-in-portugal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 14:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2019-03-06-freiheit.com-invests-in-portugal/</guid>
      <description>The founder and managing director of freiheit.com, Claudia Dietze, explained to BusinessIT that the company’s name means ‘freedom’ in German and is «related to open-source software which started spreading when the company was founded». The idea «was to be one of the best in the world, not the biggest».&#xA;Lisbon was a natural choice Claudia revealed how they proceeded. Before leaving Germany, they investigated which places had the best universities and selected three cities: Barcelona, Madrid and Lisbon: «During four weeks, we travelled, we worked in coworking spaces, we had meetings with the founders of other companies and withthe chambers of commerce».</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2018-10-16-code.talks-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 16:38:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2018-10-16-code.talks-2018/</guid>
      <description>Some people think, that managers are not needed anymore. It is widely believed, that the future belongs to agile, self-organizing teams and emergent behavior. In a world without managers, these teams operate like some kind of swarm intelligence, that always finds the right solution, at the right time, and is constantly creating the highest value for the customer, right?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-06-02-aubrey_de_grey/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2017 12:38:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-06-02-aubrey_de_grey/</guid>
      <description>On June 2, 2017, we got an awesome guest speaker at our HackerTalk - Aubrey de Grey&amp;nbsp;→, the Chief Science Officer and Co-Founder of the SENS Research Foundation&amp;nbsp;→. The foundation&amp;rsquo;s stated goal is to transform the way the world researches and treats age-related disease. Aubrey provocatively proposes that the first human beings who will live to 1,000 years old have already been born.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-05-05-marco_boerries_hackertalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 14:28:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-05-05-marco_boerries_hackertalk/</guid>
      <description>On May 5, 2017, Marco Börries&amp;nbsp;→ presents his fourth product, NumberFour, or recently branded as enfore&amp;nbsp;→. Marco Börries is a German software engineer, a business friend and partner - and passionate entrepreneur!&#xA;In his talk „Make small business work in a complex world“, he gives us an insight into his current product, his strategy as well as the architecture and technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-03-23-spiegel_online_buero_fdc/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2017 14:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-03-23-spiegel_online_buero_fdc/</guid>
      <description>SPIEGEL ONLINE compares the top 17 offices worldwide - we are in. According to a study, the productivity of each individual depends on the spatiality of the workplace. Where would you like to work?&#xA;Check it out at SPIEGEL ONLINE&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-03-03-video_cmagnussen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2017 17:19:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-03-03-video_cmagnussen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-being-scared-of-machine-learning-will-leave-you-in-the-90s&#34;&gt;Why being scared of machine learning will leave you in the 90s&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;font-serif no-underline hover:text-red&#34; href=&#34;http://christophmagnussen.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Christoph Magnussen&amp;nbsp;→&lt;/a&gt; and Stefan Richter met for a quick talk about the fear of many companies to utilize their data and the state of security when using cloud. Hope it&amp;rsquo;s useful to you guys!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Read full article to watch the video:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-01-20-huffington-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 11:43:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2017-01-20-huffington-post/</guid>
      <description>Die Maschine bekommt ein sympathisches Gesicht&amp;nbsp;→, nämlich unseres&amp;nbsp;→&#xA;Even though machines are taking over more jobs that previously have been executed by humans, this development also bears a lot of opportunities for us, because we are still a valuable workforce. Nevertheless, the population declines and becomes increasingly older and many exciting jobs still remain that only someone made out of flesh and blood can do best. At the same time, the human workforce is decreasing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-11-24-rowhow-sponsor/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Nov 2016 16:45:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-11-24-rowhow-sponsor/</guid>
      <description>From November, 25 to 27, 2016 the third Robotic Hamburg Open Workshop (RoHOW)&amp;nbsp;→ will be held at the Hamburg University of Technology (TUHH).&#xA;The RoHOW is an educational and networking event of students of the Universität Hamburg and the TUHH with students and scientists from all over the world that are active in research on humanoid robots.&#xA;Teams of the standard platform and Humanoid Kid Size League are invited to present their work.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-10-26-mathematiker-zu-besuch/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 11:56:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-10-26-mathematiker-zu-besuch/</guid>
      <description>On October 26, 2016, we hang out with these cool, young mathematicians from Lothar Collatz School&amp;nbsp;→ for Computing in Science, which promotes computational education &amp;amp; research at the interface of Mathematics, Computer Science, and Computational Sciences. It is a pleasure having you, thank you for visiting us!&#xA;Here´s more about the event&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-09-22-saalzwei_sep16/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 21:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-09-22-saalzwei_sep16/</guid>
      <description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive.&#xA;Today: Man muss kein Programmierer sein&amp;nbsp;→, um Software zu entwickeln&amp;nbsp;→.&#xA;Not so long ago, not many job positions were offered for non-engineers in the digital industry. This has changed immensely. More and more jobs are created, where even a university degree in archaeology, history, or philosophy will take you a long way in the digital industry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-code.talks2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 12:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-code.talks2016/</guid>
      <description>The code.talks&amp;nbsp;→ meanwhile is one of Europe’s biggest developer’s conference. In 2016, the developer’s bash goes into its sixth round. This time, freiheit.com is platinum sponsor and curators for track New Technology&amp;nbsp;→, Live Coding&amp;nbsp;→, and Big Data &amp;amp; Skalierung&amp;nbsp;→.&#xA;code.talks.de&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-fsfesummit2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 18:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-fsfesummit2016/</guid>
      <description>Imagine the European Union builds its IT infrastructure based on free software. Imagine European member states trade information with the help of open standards and share their software. Imagine municipalities and city councils profit from decentralized and collaborative software based on free software licenses. Imagine Europeans are no longer forced to use proprietary software any longer.&#xA;That is the goal of the FSFE&amp;nbsp;→. The FSFE Summit&amp;nbsp;→ is the general assembly that unites FSFE members and supporters from all over Europe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-openpgp206/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2016 11:44:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-openpgp206/</guid>
      <description>On September 8 and September 9, 2016, the German Unix User Group in Cologne organizes the OpenPGP.conf&amp;nbsp;→ - the first public conference with main topic OpenPGP. We are supporters because strong encryption is the most important basic technology of a free and digital future society. freiheit.com is proud to support the conference as silver sponsor.&#xA;Here’s more on the conference&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-05-12-office_snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 16:33:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-05-12-office_snapshots/</guid>
      <description>The photo blog “Office Snapshots” shows inspiring office designs from all over the globe. Along our company ethos “design follows function”, we have created a place, where both creative and analytical teams are able to ideally work in an innovative atmosphere. Office Snapshots has now published our work space among “the world’s best office designs” …&#xA;Check out Office Snapshots&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-26-saalzwei_recruiting/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 14:16:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-26-saalzwei_recruiting/</guid>
      <description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive.&#xA;In the digital age, recruiting is becoming the most important management role, which is not only executed by CEOs in Silicon Valley. In her column “Jobinterviews sind CEO-Sache”, Claudia explains the importance of a CEO’s presence and how to implement a corporate value system in today’s recruiting process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-typed_clojure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 21:04:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-08-24-typed_clojure/</guid>
      <description>Ambrose Bonnaire-Sergeant&amp;nbsp;→ starts his campaign named Typed Clojure &amp;amp; clojure.spec: Auto Annotations&amp;nbsp;→. Write tests, receive types! Type comments in Typed Clojure are large and laborious to write manually. This project comprises manufacturing of a tool for the automation of the process based on already written tests. freiheit.com is excited to be part of it as a sponsor!&#xA;Find out more about the campaign&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-22-meetup_live_coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 18:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-22-meetup_live_coding/</guid>
      <description>Our founder Stefan Richter organizes the first Live Coding Meetup in Hamburg. On May 9, 2016, we will start off the Meetup with parser combinators in Haskell. Alex Biehl is going to present the basic concept and use of parser combinators and interactively build a JSON parser and develop a personal parser combinators library on the beamer. Parsers are used almost everywhere: HTML pages in browsers, JSON, or other small, self-defined format, which need to be assembled logically for processing, in order to be mapped onto data structures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-19-codetalks_april_2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2016 18:57:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-19-codetalks_april_2016/</guid>
      <description>Thomas Storck - CIO METRO Cash &amp;amp; Carry - knows the necessity of the digital transformation. He was the driving force behind building a food delivery software to optimize his customer’s needs. METRO is at the very top of Europe’s online retailers, counting more than 3 billion euros in revenue within the food delivery business of online orders. A strong technology partner stands behind making the first step towards the future.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-01-wiwo_chefbueros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 15:29:35 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-04-01-wiwo_chefbueros/</guid>
      <description>The slideshow in the series “Chefbüro” of the German magazine “WirtschaftsWoche” (14/2016), offers us a glimpse into the offices of the best managers. Throughout the three open-spaced, modern floors of the software company freiheit.com, located in the vibrant borough St. Pauli, Claudia shows how freiheit.com’s hacker culture comes to life in the office: “German Engineering meets Silicon Valley”. The mechanical model ship displayed on Claudia’s sideboard is a gift given to her by the late NASA pioneer Prof.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-03-11-businesstalk_kirschner_fsfe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2016 15:29:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2016-03-11-businesstalk_kirschner_fsfe/</guid>
      <description>In his talk - held on March 11, 2016 - our guest speaker Matthias Kirschner, President of the Free Software Foundation Europe (FSFE), discusses the foundation’s activity, successes, and future plans. Since October 2003, bookzilla.de is operated by freiheit.com and is the world’s first online bookstore supporting free software. All proceeds are donated to FSFE by freiheit.com since 2004. The non-profit organization supports the distribution and advancement of open source programs for over 30 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-12-04-zeit_online_dez15/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 19:23:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-12-04-zeit_online_dez15/</guid>
      <description>In her interview with ZEIT ONLINE, Claudia Dietze explains why authority and responsibility need ownership, not hierarchy.&#xA;Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-10-22-online_karrieretag_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 14:03:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-10-22-online_karrieretag_2015/</guid>
      <description>On October 22, 2015, freiheit.com is a sponsor at the Online-Karrieretag in Hamburg. In his interview by Michael Karasjew (dieBewerbungsExperten.de), Stefan Richter explains what the ideal job candidate looks like.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-10-15-saalzwei_wer_braucht_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2015 18:00:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-10-15-saalzwei_wer_braucht_manager/</guid>
      <description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive. In her column titled “Wer braucht heute noch Manager?” (“Who still needs managers today?”), Claudia explains how new management concepts, such as Holacracy, leads towards meaningful tasks and better results.&#xA;Wer braucht heute noch Manager?&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-10-02-business_talk_lars_hinrichs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 13:53:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-10-02-business_talk_lars_hinrichs/</guid>
      <description>On October 2, 2015, Lars Hinrichs - Internet pioneer and founder of the career network XING - is our business talk guest and speaks about his latest project: Apartimentum - a smart home located in Hamburg.&#xA;About the project&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015_stefan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 19:20:07 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015_stefan/</guid>
      <description>Can we build an intelligent software agent, who portrays a perfect project manager? A bot who delivers information in the right time to the right people and who is both analyzer and messenger as well as helpful assistant at the same time? In September 2015, Stefan Richter speaks at the fifth code.talks conference about the usage of intelligent agents within software development.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 14:01:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-09-30-codetalks_2015/</guid>
      <description>The code.talks have grown to become one of Europe’s biggest developer conferences. In 2015, the developer’s community celebrates their reunion for the fifth time. freiheit.com is gold sponsor, once again. Stefan Richter and Martin Holtschneider are curators for tracks “New Technology” and “Scalability”, respectively.&#xA;Visit code.talks.de&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-09-10-ecml_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2015 13:51:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-09-10-ecml_2015/</guid>
      <description>In September 2015, freiheit.com sponsors the ECML PKDD in Porto. The ECML is a machine learning conference, which takes place annually in different European locations. Our colleague Michael Großhans is a guest speaker at the conference, presenting the topic “Solving Prediction Games with Parallel Batch Gradient Descent”.&#xA;Paper and abstract&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-08-17-sylt_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Aug 2015 19:17:47 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-08-17-sylt_2015/</guid>
      <description>A day at sea with freiheit.com. It is a perfect day for a company trip to the beautiful island of Sylt, on this amazing, sunny summer’s day in the month of August, 2015. With plenty of chilled drinks and tasty food, we are spending a relaxed day, playing beach volleyball, trying ourselves at “Viking Chess”, and playing the guitar in the Western part of Kampen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-08-01-claudia_charmante_mrs_perfect/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2015 13:56:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-08-01-claudia_charmante_mrs_perfect/</guid>
      <description>In the newspaper series of the Hamburger Abendblatt “Der Rote Faden” (“The Red Thread”), which symbolizes a connection between people who respect and appreciate each other. XING founder Lars Hinrichs has extended the red thread to Claudia Dietze. In the following article, entrepreneur Claudia Dietze explains why to her reason and passion are not contrary to one another.&#xA;Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-07-01-saalzwei_maker/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 18:03:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-07-01-saalzwei_maker/</guid>
      <description>Claudia Dietze - columnist for the online magazine SAAL ZWEI - writes exclusively about topics that move her in her daily life as top executive.&#xA;Makers determine a company’s future - why? Claudia provides an answer in her column “Sind Sie ein &amp;lsquo;Maker&amp;rsquo; oder verwalten Sie?” (“Are you a ‘maker’ or are you an administrator?”).&#xA;Sind Sie ein &amp;lsquo;Maker&amp;rsquo; oder verwalten Sie?&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-06-16-tag_der_offenen_tuer_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 13:41:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-06-16-tag_der_offenen_tuer_2015/</guid>
      <description>Open House @ freiheit.com. On June 19, 2015, we are inviting friends and family of our colleagues to freiheit.com’s Open House, showing how exciting the work of a software engineer can be. After a tour through freiheit.com laboratories, we are inviting all of our guests to a summer BBQ on our panoramic rooftop terrace, overlooking St. Pauli.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-06-10-perfect_the_enemy_of_good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 19:14:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-06-10-perfect_the_enemy_of_good/</guid>
      <description>manager magazin - a German monthly magazine focusing on business, finance and management - publishes a collection of the best advices given in the SAAL ZWEI interview series “3 FRAGEN AN 30 FRAUEN.” (“3 QUESTIONS FOR 30 WOMEN.”). Amongst them, Claudia Dietze’s SAAL ZWEI column “Perfect is the enemy of good” has also been selected.&#xA;Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-04-26-js_unconf_2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2015 13:35:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2015-04-26-js_unconf_2015/</guid>
      <description>JS Unconf is a non-profit conference of the JavaScript community. In 2015, freiheit.com is one of the sponsors. The audience has chosen our colleague Michael Bohn to speak about “Displaying, Animating, and Comunicating with Ponies in famo.us”. Michael is providing both his presentation and demo app on our GitHub account.&#xA;Click here for the presentation&amp;nbsp;→&#xA;Check out the demo app&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-12-17-saal_zwei_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2014 19:08:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-12-17-saal_zwei_2014/</guid>
      <description>In the SAAL ZWEI column “3 QUESTIONS FOR 30 WOMEN.” the online magazine introduces 30 female top managers, who are all game changers in their industries. Among them is Claudia Dietze, who is convinced that most of the time perfect is the enemy of good. Along this corporate principle and for more than 15 years, she has been successfully leading her company towards the future.&#xA;Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-11-20-vdz_tech_summit_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 14:13:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-11-20-vdz_tech_summit_2014/</guid>
      <description>Stefan Richter holds his presentation “Von Big Data zum Machine Learning” (“From Big Data to Machine Learning”) during the second VDZ Tech Summit on November 20, 2014. His presentation illustrates how user behavior can be made transparent through data analysis and its evaluation, in order to better understand the client&amp;rsquo;s needs and for automated optimization for processes, products, and services.&#xA;Check out the interview&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-11-01-absatzwirtschaft/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 19:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-11-01-absatzwirtschaft/</guid>
      <description>Claudia Dietze speaks about the necessity of establishing detailed data of client behavior as a key to success but also respecting both privacy and informational self-determination.&#xA;Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 14:11:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-10-01-code.talks_2014/</guid>
      <description>Artificial neural networks have a major technological potential. Meanwhile, many open source machine learning software libraries exist in order to experiment with deep artificial neural networks, i.e. TensorFlow or Torch. In his presentation “Machine Learning mit künstlichen neuronalen Netzwerken in Clojure” (“Machine Learning with Artificial Neural Networks in Clojure”), Stefan Richter shows us - during the fourth code.talks in 2014 - how exciting it is to build one&amp;rsquo;s own library for artificial neural networks in Clojure.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-06-06-wir_haben_eine_hackerkultur/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2014 13:58:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2014-06-06-wir_haben_eine_hackerkultur/</guid>
      <description>Claudia Dietze speaks of the necessity of transferring standard business models into the digital world and, furthermore, about freiheit.com’s hacker culture. freiheit.com is one of 900.000 mid-sized business customers of Deutsche Bank.&#xA;Check out the article&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2010-09-24-hack_fwd_2010/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Sep 2010 19:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2010-09-24-hack_fwd_2010/</guid>
      <description>Stefan Richter not only was a board member of HackFwd - a startup founded by Lars Hinrichs - but at the same time he also founded the startup project “TheDeadline”. The project made freiheit.com an early adopter of HTML5, Clojure, cloud-based NoSQL database, and smartphone clients with offline syncing. In 2010, at one of the HackFwd Build Conferences on Mallorca, Stefan explains the technical architecture of the system.&#xA;Check out his presentation&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2010-02-02-clojure_pet_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2010 13:44:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2010-02-02-clojure_pet_project/</guid>
      <description>Since freiheit.com was founded, we have built our own tools adopting early techniques of AI and Machine Learning, helping us to effectively and efficiently manage software projects: from early XMPP bots over prolog backend and Rete algorithm-based production systems for a rule-based expert system for task management written in Clojure. This even became a small startup project: “How a Clojure pet project turned into a full-blown cloud-computing web app”.&#xA;Check out the event&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2005-06-04-survival_of_the_fittest/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2005 14:05:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/chronicle/2005-06-04-survival_of_the_fittest/</guid>
      <description>The LinuxTag is a fantastic event for programmers and free software activists. Already in 2005, Stefan has expressed interest in Objective-C and GNUstep environment. But a pet project was missing in order to learn the language. The outcome was a presentation at the LinuxTag about algorithms in Objective-C, with which Guile Scheme programs for GNU Robot could genetically be optimized.&#xA;Read the entire paper here&amp;nbsp;→</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>And There Is More</title>
      <link>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/and-there-is-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2000 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://mploigt.github.io/freiheit/things-weve-build/and-there-is-more/</guid>
      <description>We have built lottery platforms (business model: selling random numbers) and dating platforms (business model: selling contacts between customers). The internet is full of interesting new ideas and we are sure that this is still just the beginning.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
